Vyron Vasileiadis

Software Engineer & Trainer

Personal Info

E-mail

hi@fedonman.com

WWW

https://fedonman.com

LinkedIn

https://linkedin.com/in/fedonman

Skills

Web Development

Game Development

Machine & Deep Learning

Internet of Things

Remote Sensing

Microsoft Azure

Training & Coaching

Problem Solving

Software

C#

ASP.NET

Entity Framework

HTML

Software engineer specialized in web technologies and Microsoft Azure with a keen interest and variable experience in machine & deep learning, IoT, smart cities, ocean remote sensing and quantum computing.

Microsoft Certified Trainer adept at planning and implementing onsite and remote training programs with 1000+ teaching hours and 400+ students. Authoritative and clear communicator with a charismatic style and insightful approach.

Based in Athens, Greece. Open to remote positions or attractive relocation packages.

Work History

2019-01 -Current

Microsoft Certified Trainer

Freelancer, Worldwide

Scheduled and taught various in-class and online Microsoft courses either independently or in cooperation with Microsoft Partners. Currently available courses:

- Microsoft Azure Fundamentals
- Designing and Implementing an Azure Al Solution
- Designing and Implementing a Data Science Solution on Azure
- Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3
- Programming in C#
- Developing ASP.NET MVC Web Applications

2016-10 -2020-01

ICT Trainer

PeopleCert, Athens, Greece

- Trainer at Alliance for Digital Employability Coding Bootcamp, a 14-week intensive training course, where previously unemployed candidates with no ICT background are re-skilled and certified by PeopleCert as full-stack developers
- Trained over 1000 hours and more than 400 students
 Python, C#, ASP.NET, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
 Angular, React, as well as generic software skills such
 as algorithms, design patterns, OOP, functional
 programming, testing, scrum
- Mentored and coached students about their projects in an simulated agile environment

CSS

JavaScript

React

Angular

Aurelia

Python

Azure DevOps

 Collaborated with leadership to assist in lesson plans, instructional materials and written practice tests

2014-09 -2017-04

Co-Founder & Lead Developer

Open.tech, Athens, Greece

- Co-Founder of open.tech, a collaborative creative agency in Greece specialized in innovative technologies and the web
- Lead Developer on a plethora of projects for a variety of clients including luxury villas, apartments and hotels, top Greek fashion designers, theatrical groups and the Greek government
- Worked closely with clients to establish problem specifications and system designs
- Managed a team of 5 developers and designers

2013-10 -2014-06

Web & Game Developer

Pegneon, Athens, Greece

- Implemented company's website, API and integrated solutions into business operations
- Designed and developed company's main product, an educational game about safety and hygiene in co-working spaces
- As the sole developer of the company, i had elevated architecture responsibilities

2012-05 -2012-10

Web Developer

IT Development Spain, Granada, Spain

- Researched new technologies, software packages and hardware products for use in website projects
- Used various technologies to make code repairs and optimize corporate website

Education

2015-10 -2017-10

Master of Science: Space Science, Technologies & Applications

University of Peloponnese & National Observatory of Athens - Greece

- The first and only Higher Education Programme in Greece in the domain of Space
- Thesis: "Advancements in monitoring the

2007-10 -2013-03

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science & Technology

University of Peloponnese - Greece

- Thesis: "CoveX: Quantum Circuit Simulator"
- Elected as Student's Representative for 4 consecutive years

Additional Training

- Copernicus Marine Service for the Aquaculture Sector, Athens, Greece, 24 - 25 September 2019
- ESA Advanced Ocean Remote Sensing Training
 Course at Porto, Portugal, 11 17 September 2017
- Third International Ocean Colour Science Meeting at Lisbon, Portugal, 15-18 May 2017
- Quantum Complex Systems Summer School at University of Vienna, Austria, 22 - 26 September 2014
- Workshop on Quantum Simulations at Universidad del Pais Vasco UPV/EHU, Bilbao, Spain, 22-25 October 2012

Certifications

| 2019-01 | Microsoft Certified Trainer |
|---------|---|
| 2019-01 | Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate: Web Development |
| 2019-06 | Microsoft Certified: Azure Al Engineer Associate |
| 2019-06 | NVIDIA Deep Learning for Computer Vision |
| 2019-10 | Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Scientist Associate |

Speaking Sessions

Doing AI the Cloud Way: Enterprise Azure Machine Learning

Microsoft Ignite the Tour, Amsterdam, Netherlands, 11 - 12 March 2020, Breakout Session (45 minutes)

Intelliwaste: An awarded integrated smart waste management solution powered by Azure

Microsoft Ignite the Tour, Amsterdam, Netherlands, 11 - 12 March 2020, Theater Session (15 minutes)

Volunteering

- Technical Trainer at Social Hackers Academy, an NGO programming school for refugees & unemployed EU Nationals
- Mentor at a plethora of innovation hackathons co-organized by Crowdpolicy and Greek public sector

Awarded Projects

Intelliwaste

Awarded 3rd out of 167 contestants @ City Challenge Crowdhackathon #smartcity 2

Waste management and recycling is a fundamental part of a sustainable economy. For more efficient and safe recycling, it is necessary to use intelligent systems instead of employing humans as workers in the dump-yards. Intelliwaste solution utilizes IoT Edge bins that accomplice waste classification at source using Deep Learning algorithms and real-time waste management using ultrasonic and bridge sensors. The solution is backed by sophisticated software (analytics, route planning, and management), providing cities with data-driven decision making and optimization of waste collection routes, frequencies, and vehicle loads. The result is a dramatic increase in recycling rate and overall waste collection cost and carbon emission reduction.